Guide to the UE National Office Records Relating to District 2 and District 2 Locals, 1936-1994 UE.4.1.2
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- District 2 Locals, 2.
  - Local 292 (Producto)
    - Local 292 (Producto) Outgoing Correspondence, May 11, 1951-Januayr 19, 1954 (Box 15, Folder 48)
      - Harry Kaplan to Emspak Regarding International Harvester Strikes, November 1952; 2.
      - Julius Medivis to UE Regarding Finances, May 11, 1951; 3.
    - Local 292 (Producto) Organization (Box 15, Folder 49)
    - Local 292 (Producto) Embezzlement, November 15, 1951-March 12, 1952 (Box 15, Folder 50)
      - Julius Medvin Confession, November 15, 1951; 1.
      - Albert Olson to David Rutner, March 10, 1952; 2.
      - Olson to Rutner, March 12, 1952; 3.
    - Local 292 (Producto) Correspondence, July 18, 1952-January 3, 1955 (Box 15, Folder 51)
      - Harry Kaplan to UE Fighting Fund Regarding Fighting Fund, July 18, 1952; 1.
      - Kaplan to David Ratner Regarding Finances, January 3, 1955; 2.
  - Local 293
    - Local 293 Officers Lists, 1948-1949 (Box 15, Folder 52)
    - Local 293 Incoming Correspondence, April 24, 1947-June 22, 1950 (Box 15, Folder 53)
      - Julius Emspak to Harold Dearman Regarding Local 293 Chartering, April 24, 1947; 1.
      - Emspak to John Volturno Regarding Political Action Committee, December 2, 1947-Aprili 6, 1948; 2-4.
      - Emspak to Dearman Regarding Finances, July 28-April 11, 1949; 5-6.
      - Emspak to Dearman Regarding UE News and Bridgeport, May 27, 1949; 7.
      - Emspak to Frank Avlio Regarding Finances, June 22, 1950; 8.
    - Local 293 Outgoing Correspondence, November 17, 1947-June 26, 1956 (Box 15, Folder 54)
      - Harold Dearman to Julius Emspak Regarding Finances, April 7, 1949; 1.
      - Domenic Fiovini to Emspak Regarding Finances, June 26, 1956; 2.
      - John Volturno to UE Regarding Political Action Committee, November 17, 1947; 3.
    - Local 293 Correspondence, September 27, 1972-March 20, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 55)
    - Local 293 Organization, April 24, 1947 (Box 15, Folder 56)
      - Julius Emspak to Paul Seymour, April 24, 1947; 1.
      - Emspak to Albert Smith, April 24, 1947; 2.
  - Local 294
    - Local 294 Correspondence, October 24, 1974-June 29, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 57)
    - Local 294 Dover Macallen Plant, April 8, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 58)
    - Local 294 Greenland Sylvania GTE, June 24, 1976-February 23, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 59)
    - Local 294 Strikes, Subsidies and Other Monies, July 16, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 60)
  - Local 294 (Worcester)
    - Local 294 (Worcester) Officers Lists, June 12, 1947 (Box 15, Folder 61)
    - Local 294 (Worcester) Incoming Correspondence, Julius Emspak to George Perron Regarding St. Pierre Chain Organization, June 12, 1947 (Box 15, Folder 62)
    - Local 294 (Worcester) Financial, June 12-July 28, 1947 (Box 15, Folder 63)
      - Charter Supplies, June 12, 1947; 1.
      - Voucher, July 28, 1947; 2.
    - Local 294 (Worcester) Organization, June 4-12, 1947 (Box 15, Folder 64)
      - Martin Williams to James Matles with Membership Cards, June 4, 1947; 1.
      - Williams to Matles, June 5, 1947; 2.
      - Julius Emspak to WIlliams, June 9-12, 1947; 3-4.
      - Emspak to Paul Seymour, June 12, 1947; 5.
    - Local 294 (Worcester) Strikes, August 1-19, 1947 (Box 15, Folder 65)
      - Report of Strike, August 1, 1947; 1.
      - Donald Tormey to James Matles, August 2, 1947; 2.
      - Paul Seymour Telegram to Julius Emspak, August 19, 1947; 3.
  - Local 294 (Hartford)
    - Local 294 (Hartford) Incoming Correspondence, Julius Emspak to Michael Fiederowccz, August 4, 1950 (Box 15, Folder 66)
    - Local 294 (Hartford) Outgoing Correspondence, Francis Sullivan to UE Regarding International Harvester Strikes, November 13, 1952-October 30, 1956 (Box 15, Folder 67)
    - Local 294 (Hartford) Organization, January 5-February 8, 1950 (Box 15, Folder 68)
      - Julius Emspak to Albert Smith, January 5, 1950; 1.
      - Emspak's Secretary to Smith, February 8, 1950; 2.
  - Local 295
    - Local 295 Membership List, February 17, 1940 (Box 15, Folder 69)
    - Local 295 Incoming Correspondence, July 24, 1947-May 3, 1955 (Box 15, Folder 70)
      - Julius Emspak to Anna Whipple Regarding Bijur Lubricating and Ed. Sibley Manufacturing, July 24, 1947; 1.
      - Emspak to Charles Tidd Regarding Veterans and Dues, March 16, 1948; 2.
      - Emspak to Howard Fitzgerald Regarding Bijur Lubricating Strikes, December 14, 1949-January 4, 1950; 3-6.
      - Emspak to Edward Myres Regarding Finances, December 6, 1950; 7.
      - James Matles to J. A. Noble Regarding Membership Meeting, March 3, 1955; 8.
    - Local 295 Outgoing Correspondence, November 15, 1948-November 19, 1949 (Box 15, Folder 71)
      - Luther Graves to UE Regarding Local 295 Bijur Lubricating Strikes and Runaway Shops, November 15, 1948; 1.
      - James Noble to Julius Emspak Regarding Local 295 Bijur Lubricating Strikes and Shops, November 19, 1949; 2.
    - Local 295 Bington Correspondence, November 26, 1956-December 5, 1967 (Box 15, Folder 72)
    - Local 295 Organization, July 15-24, 1947 (Box 15, Folder 73)
      - Gerard Steinberg to Julius Emspak, July 15, 1947; 1.
      - Emspak to Steinberg, July 17, 1947; 2.
      - Charter Supplement Application, July 21, 1947; 3.
      - Emspak to Steinberg, July 24, 1947; 4.
      - Emspak to Paul Seymour, July 24, 147; 5.
    - Local 295 Bennington, May 11, 1983-August 3, 1986 (Box 15, Folder 74)
    - Local 295 Pension Correspondence, Strike, Subsidies and Other Monies, December 19, 1967-May 2, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 75)
    - Local 295 Legislation Committee and Political Action, April 20, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 76)
    - Local 295 Notifications and Correspondence, October 28, 1948-December 2, 1956 (Box 15, Folder 77)
      - Notification of Pending Disagreement Regarding Bijur Lubricating, October 28, 1948-October 21, 1949; 1-2.
      - Paul Seymour to Julius Emspak Regarding International Harvester Strikes, December 2, 1956; 3.
      - Seymour to Emspak Regarding Finances, December 2, 1953; 4.
  - Local 296
    - Local 296 Officers Lists, July 24, 1947-December 8, 1949 (Box 15, Folder 78)
    - Local 296 Wallingford Stone Safety Contracts, June 1, 1987-June 30, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 79)
    - Local 296 Incoming Correspondence, Julius Emspak to Theresa Widing Regarding Telechron Organization, July 24, 1947 (Box 15, Folder 80)
    - Local 296 Correspondence, April 20, 1960-May 1, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 81)
    - Local 296 Wallingford Stone Safety Correspondence and Clippings, June 4, 1979-December 8, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 82)
    - Local 296 Wallingford Stone Safety Equipment Finances, April 19, 1968-March 26, 1986 (Box 15, Folder 83)
    - Local 296 Receipt with Note, April 11, 1950 (Box 15, Folder 84)
    - Local 296 Organization, July 23-24, 1947 (Box 15, Folder 85)
      - Donald Tormey to Julius Emspak, July 23, 1947; 1.
      - Emspak to Martin Williams, July 24, 1947; 2.
      - Emspak to Paul Seymour, July 24, 1947; 3.
    - Local 296 New Haven Safety Electrical Equipment Corporation, April 22, 1982-December 12, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 86)
    - Local 296 Stone Safety Occupational Safety and Health Material, October 23, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 87)
    - Local 296 Incorrect Check, April 24, 1947-April 26, 1950 (Box 15, Folder 88)
      - Julius Emspak to Worcester County Trust Company, April 24, 1947; 1.
      - Ron Davis to Emspak, April 26, 1950; 2.
  - Local 297
    - Local 297 Vulkor, July 28, 1944-September 18, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 89)
    - Local 297 Vulkor Correspondence and Clippings, October 7, 1987-July 25, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 90)
    - Local 297 Vulkor Pension Plan, December 1987-February 1988 (Box 15, Folder 91)
  - Local 297 (Lowell)
    - Local 297 (Lowell) Incoming Correspondence, August 26, 1947-August 8, 1949 (Box 15, Folder 92)
      - Julius Emspak to Daniel Hilliaid Regarding Lowell 6E Organization, August 26, 1947; 1.
      - Emspak to Hilliaid Regarding Veterans and Dues, October 23, 1947; 2.
      - Emspak to Hilliaid Regarding Political Action Committee, December 17, 1947; 3.
      - Emspak to Robert Shea Regarding Finances, September 22, 1948; 4.
      - Emspak to Shea Regarding Finances, May 9, 1949; 5.
      - Emspak to Beatrice Lemire Regarding Plant Closure and Finances, August 8, 1949; 6.
    - Local 297 (Lowell) Outgoing Correspondence, October 17, 1947-May 7, 1949 (Box 15, Folder 93)
      - Florence Donohue to Julius Emspak Regarding Political Action Committee, December 10, 1947; 1.
      - Daniel Hilliaid to Emspak Regarding Veterans and Dues, October 17, 1947; 2.
      - Beatrice Lemire to UE Regarding Finances, January 29, 1949; 3.
      - Lemire to UE Regarding Plant Closures and Local 297 Disbanding, August 1949; 4.
      - Robert Shea to Emspak Regarding Finances, August 21, 1948-May 7, 1949; 5-6.
    - Local 297 (Lowell) Correspondence, March 16, 1970-May 4, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 94)
    - Local 297 (Lowell) Correspondence, April 27, 1956-May 18, 1967 (Box 15, Folder 95)
    - Local 297 (Lowell) Receipts, June 1948-July 1949 (Box 15, Folder 96)
    - Local 297 (Lowell) Organization, August 22-26, 1947 (Box 15, Folder 97)
      - Nat Shelman to Albert Smith, August 22, 1947; 1.
      - Smith to Julius Emspak, August 25, 1947; 2.
      - Emspak to Paul Seymour, August 26, 1947; 3.
      - Emspak to Smith, August 26, 1947; 4.
      - Emspak to Shelman, August 26, 1947; 5.
    - Local 297 (Lowell) Taft-Hartley Classes, September 9-15, 1947 (Box 15, Folder 98)
      - Nat Shelman to David Scribner, September 9, 1947; 1.
      - Scribner to Shelman, September 15, 1947; 2.
    - Local 297 (Lowell) Loan and Kehoe Case, April 1, 1975-May 12, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 99)
    - Local 297 (Lowell) Plant Closure and Local Disbanding, September 3-6, 1949 (Box 15, Folder 100)
      - Julius Emspak to Paul Seymour, September 3, 1949; 1.
      - Seymour to Emspak, September 6, 1949; 2.
    - Local 297 (Lowell) Strikes, Subsidies and Other Monies, January 15-27, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 101)
  - Local 297 (Marginal Street)
    - Local 297 (Marginal Street) Incoming Correspondence, May 2, 1951-July 26, 1955 (Box 15, Folder 102)
      - Julius Emspak to Thomas Hodge Regarding Per Capita, May 2, 1951; 1.
      - Emspak to Paul Trowdridge Regarding Finances, February 3, 1953; 2.
      - Emspak to Hodge Regarding Finances, March 18, 1953-July 26, 1955; 3-4.
    - Local 297 (Marginal Street) Outgoing Correspondence, February 19, 1951-January 28, 1953 (Box 15, Folder 103)
      - Thomas Dalton to Julius Emspak Regarding Dues Check-off and Unemployment, February 19, 1951; 1.
      - Robert Donohue to Joseph Dermody Regarding Per Capita, Factionalism and Anti-communism, January 18, 1951; 2.
      - Thomas Hodge to Emspak Regarding Finances, April 25, 1951; 3.
      - Hodge to Emspak Regarding International Harvester Strikes, November 6, 1952; 4.
      - Hodge to Paul Seymour Regarding Workmen's Compensation and Finances, December 31, 1952; 5.
      - Hodge to Emspak Regarding Dues and Finances, March 9, 1953; 6.
      - Hodge to Seymour Regarding Dues and Finances, March 9, 1953; 7.
      - Paul Trowbridge to Emspak Regarding Dues, Per Capita, Incentive and Factionalism, January 28, 1953; 8.
    - Local 297 (Marginal Street) Organization, 1950 (Box 15, Folder 104)
      - Donald Bollen to Julius Emspak, March 15, 1950; 1.
      - Emspak to Bollen, March 20, 1950; 2.
      - Madeline Memo, 1950; 3.
      - Rachie Memo to Caroline, 1950; 4.
    - Local 297 (Marginal Street) Correspondence, January 21, 1953-July 15, 1955 (Box 15, Folder 105)
      - Paul Seymour to Julius Emspak Regarding Finances and Dues, January 21, 1953; 1.
      - Seymour to Emspak Regarding Finances with July 12, 1955, Thomas Hodge Letter to Seymour, July 15, 1955; 2.
  - Local 298
    - Local 298 Officers Lists, March 1948-January 1949 (Box 15, Folder 106)
    - Local 298 Incoming Correspondence, Julius Emspak to Robert O'Mahoney Regarding Bridgeport and UE News, May 27, 1949 (Box 15, Folder 107)
    - Local 298 Outgoing Correspondence, October 4, 1948-August 23, 1954 (Box 15, Folder 108)
      - Nicholas Fortino to Albert Fitzgerald Regarding Local 298 MB Manufacturing and Textron Purchase, August 23, 1954; 1.
      - Robert Mahoney to Julius Emspak Regarding Taft-Hartley, Membership and Finances, October 4, 1948; 2.
    - Local 298 Organization, October 8-21, 1947 (Box 15, Folder 109)
      - Thomas Fitzpatrick to Julius Emspak, October 8, 1947; 1.
      - Emspak to Paul Seymour, October 21, 1947; 2.
      - Emspak to William Wilder, October 21, 1947; 3.
      - Emspak to Fitzpatrick, October 21, 1947; 4.
    - Local 298 Correspondence, January 26, 1949-July 14, 1954 (Box 15, Folder 110)
      - Kathie Memo to Trade Union Service Regarding Unemployment and Mailing List, January 26, 1949; 1.
      - Albert Smith to Julius Emspak Regarding Mailing List, February 24, 1950; 2.
      - Emspak to Paul Seymour Regarding MB Manufacturing, July 14, 1954; 3.
    - Local 298 New Haven Plant Closed Correspondence, May 2, 1950-June 15, 1973 (Box 15, Folder 111)
  - Local 299
    - Local 299 American Tube Bending Contracts, August 10, 1966-November 7, 1985 (Box 15, Folder 112)
    - Local 299 Harloc Products Contracts, March 21-November 23, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 113)
    - Local 299 Incoming Correspondence, Julius Emspak to Paul Seymour Regarding Local 299 Chartering, July 14, 1954 (Box 15, Folder 114)
    - Local 299 Outgoing Correspondence, William Zemmerman to James Matles, December 8, 1955 (Box 15, Folder 115)
    - Local 299 New Haven Correspondence, September 24, 1956-November 11, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Local 299 Correspondence, May 12, 1963-May 27, 1980 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Local 299 American Tube Bending Correspondence and Clippings, February 24, 1977-December 30, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Local 299 Nutmeg Steel Castings, March 26, 1987-January 22, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Local 299 Strikes, Subsidies and Other Monies, October 13, 1980-August 31, 1981 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Local 299 Weekley Accounting for Strike Receipts and Disbursments, March 3-August 18, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Local 299 Weekley Accounting for Strike Receipts and Disbursments, August 29-December 15, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Local 299 Weekley Accounting for Strike Receipts and Disbursments, September 12, 1989-February 24, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Local 299 New Haven Correspondence, April 25, 1980-November 7, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 9)